(
"ai_sub_version": "1.11.0",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 3,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
これは僕らのキセキ。
This is our miracle.
僕とキミと、大切なあのこの
この王国で過ごす、かけがえのない日々を綴る
Recounting the irreplaceable days spent in this kingdom
with you, me, and that precious person.
僕たちの物語。
This is our story.
僕の居る意味はどこにあるの？
Where is the meaning of my existence?
誰かに必要とされたかった
I wanted to be needed by someone.
夢や希望も捨てきれないけど
I can't quite throw away my dreams and hopes, but
なんとなく今を生きている
I'm just living for now, somehow.
ああ どれだけ叫んでも
Ah, no matter how much I scream,
この声は君には届かない
this voice won't reach you.
ああ どれだけ叫んでも
Ah, no matter how much I scream,
この声は君には届かない
this voice won't reach you.
金木犀の匂いがした
I smelled the scent of osmanthus.
明日のことも忘れたくなった
I wanted to forget about tomorrow, too.
いっそ逃げてしまおうかな
Maybe I should just run away instead.
僕は悲劇の主人公だ
I am the protagonist of a tragedy.
やさしいヒトで居たいな
I want to be a kind person.
でもそんな思いも偽善だ
But even that thought is hypocrisy.
誰も幸せにできないの
I can't make anyone happy.
都合良いね、涙が出るの
How convenient, the tears are falling.
ああ　どれだけ歌っても
Ah, no matter how much I sing,
この声は君には届かない
This voice won't reach you.
ああ　どれだけ歌っても
Ah, no matter how much I sing,
この声は君には届かない
This voice won't reach you.
ああ　息が苦しくなる
Ah, it's getting hard to breathe,
この歌もいつしか終わりが来る
This song, too, will eventually come to an end.
ああ　息が苦しくなる
Ah, it's getting hard to breathe,
この地球もいつかは終わりが来る
This planet, too, will eventually come to an end.
金木犀の匂いをまた
The scent of osmanthus once again...
思い出した
I remembered.
In the dusk,
amid the wintry wind...
The shadow of a girl...
Suddenly, the prologue begins.
気付けば…駆けだしていた…
Before I knew it... I was running...
揺れ動く…心のままに…
Following... my swaying heart...
遠ざかる…白い壁…
Fading away... the white wall...
一度も…振り返らずに…
Without... looking back once...
《生命》が…消え逝く季節の…
In the season... where life fades away...
胸を刺す…気配の中で…
Amidst the feeling... that pierces my chest...
迫りくる…暗闇…
The approaching... darkness...
二度と…明けぬような気がして…
Feeling like... it would never dawn again...
転がり落ちそうな心
A heart that seemed like it would roll and fall,
必死に抱き止めていた…
I was desperately holding onto it...
星空へと続く長い坂道は
Because the long slope leading to the starry sky,
永遠にも…思えたから――
Seemed... even like eternity—
咲く花や…散りぬるを…
The flowers that bloom... and fall...
神代の《時代》より繰り返す…
Repeating since the age of the gods...
私はそれを…美しいとは…
I have never... thought of that...
思ったことがない…
as being beautiful...
久方の…春の陽を…
Scramble for the long-awaited spring sunlight,
仮初めの影が奪い合う…
scrambled for by transient shadows...
その営みを…美しいとは…
I have never... thought of that way of life...
思ったことがない…
as being beautiful...
諦めながら…生きてた…
I lived... while giving up...
何も望まないように　それでも…
Trying not to wish for anything, and yet...
手放せなかった…最後の願いを…
I couldn't let go... Grasping my last wish,
握りしめて駆け上がる
I run up.
尾丸ポルカ
Omaru Polka
猫又おかゆ
Nekomata Okayu
大神ミオ
Ookami Mio
天音かなた
Amane Kanata
さくらみこ
Sakura Miko
鷹嶺ルイ
Takane Lui
フワワ・アビスガード　モココ・アビスガード
Fuwawa Abyssgard, Mococo Abyssgard
白上フブキ
Shirakami Fubuki
冥界 Halloween Night! FBKINGDOM
Underworld Halloween Night! FBKINGDOM
我武者羅に生きるお前が笑われて
In a world where you, living recklessly, are laughed at,
楽に生きる奴らが徳をする世界で？
and those who live easy lives profit?
我だけはお前のことを笑わない！
I'm the only one who won't laugh at you!
皆が指差し笑おうとも我は笑わない！
Even if everyone points and laughs, I won't laugh!
ああ人は滅んでゆく　綻んでゆく
Ah, people are perishing, falling apart,
才を妬み合い富を奪い合い
envying talent and scrambling for wealth.
ああ人は滅んでゆく　綻んでゆく
Ah, people are perishing, falling apart.
その果てに見えた海は　地獄だろうか？それとも地獄だろうか？
The sea seen at the end... Is it hell? Or is it hell?
我武者羅に生きるお前が笑われて
In a world where you, living recklessly, are laughed at,
楽に生きる奴らが徳をする世界で？
and those who live easy lives profit?
我だけはお前のことを笑わない！
I'm the only one who won't laugh at you!
皆が指差し笑おうとも我は笑わない！
Even if everyone points and laughs, I will not laugh!
正直に生きるお前が貶されて
You, who live honestly, are disparaged
嘘で生きる奴らが徳となる世界で
In a world where those who live on lies are rewarded
我だけはお前の腕を離さない！
I alone will not let go of your arm!
時を刻み忘れようとも我は離さない！
Even if I forget the passing of time, I won't let go!
我は忘れない！
I will not forget!
身を粉にして働いても
Even if I work myself to the bone
感謝されないことも...
And am not thanked for it...
「自己犠牲」を受け容れても
Even if I accept "self-sacrifice"
限界がもうやってくるから
Because the limit is already coming
自分を大事に愛せばいい
Just love and cherish yourself
それは他人を愛すること
That is to love others
あぁ人は滅んでゆく
Ah, people are perishing
淀んでゆく
Stagnating
元に戻ってゆく
Returning to how they were
あぁ人は泳いでゆく
Ah, people are swimming
救われてゆく
Being saved
君に逢えたから...
Because I met you...
君を愛したから...
Because I loved you...
君が戦うなら...
If you fight...
僕も戦うから
I will fight too
我武者羅に生きるお前が笑われて
You, who live recklessly, are laughed at
楽に生きる奴らが徳をする世界で
In a world where those who live easily benefit
我だけはお前のことを笑わない！
I alone will not laugh at you!
皆が指差し笑おうとも我は笑わない！
Even if everyone points and laughs, I will not laugh!
正直に生きるお前が貶されて
You, who live honestly, are disparaged
嘘で生きる奴らが徳となる世界で
In a world where those who live on lies are rewarded
我だけはお前の腕を離さない！
I alone will not let go of your arm!
時を刻み忘れようとも我は離さない！
Even if I forget the passing of time, I won't let go!
我は忘れない！
I will not forget!
それじゃあ今夜は、この王国のお話をしていこう。
Well then, tonight, let's talk about this kingdom.
嘘か真か、ここに記されている本は
Whether it's a lie or the truth, the book recorded here
内容がコロコロと変わってしまう、不思議な本でね。
has contents that change all the time; it's a mysterious book.
さて、今回はどんなお話になっているかな。
Now, I wonder what kind of story it has become this time.
これは、あるサーカスの一団が王国を訪れ、
This is a story of a certain circus troupe visiting the kingdom,
まだ未熟な座長さんが、煌びやかなステージに包まれたお話。
and a still inexperienced troupe leader being enveloped by a brilliant stage.
あぁ...これが私が望んだ夢のエンディング！
Ah... this is the dream ending I wished for!
さあ、今日も始まりました〜！
Well, it has begun today as well!
煌びやか、享楽のパレード
A brilliant parade of pleasure
常識もここじゃ無関係
Common sense is irrelevant here
踊れ歌え騒げ全て忘れて
Dance, sing, make noise, forget everything
細かいことは置いといて
Put the details aside for now
とりあえず身を任せてみな
Just try to surrender yourself
幸福を少し分けるような饗宴
A banquet that seems to share a bit of happiness
Show Time!
積もりゆく不安や後悔
Accumulating anxiety and regret
今だけはちょっと目を背けて
Just for now, look away for a bit
そのままじゃ楽しめないじゃん
You can't enjoy it as you are, right?
この場だけは何もかもを忘れて
Forget everything, just for this place
幾千の価値観全部
Thousands of values, all of them
引っくるめ楽しませたげる！
I'll bundle them up and entertain you!
百鬼夜行もビックリの
Even the Night Parade of One Hundred Demons would be surprised
隊を成している
They are forming a troop
怪奇模した喜劇が幕開け
A comedy imitating the bizarre begins
一目見ればたちまち虜に！？
If you take a look, you'll instantly be captivated!?
どんな愛も受け入れてくれる
Accepting any kind of love
ここだけはあなたの理想郷
Only here is your utopia
「もう間もなく主役の登場、
The protagonist will appear very soon,
一時でも目を離さないで！」
Don't take your eyes off for even a moment!"
眩いほどのステージが始まる。
A dazzling stage begins.
騒々して
Noisily
華々しいスポットライトの中
In the middle of the brilliant spotlight
目を奪うような妙技の数々
Numerous eye-catching feats
この空間が世界で一番
This space is the best in the world
“娯楽”の名に相応しいんだ！
It's worthy of the name "entertainment"!
割れんばかりの歓声と拍手で
With deafening cheers and applause
ショーは終わっていく
The show is coming to an end
「まあ、これはあくまで理想の話なんですが^^;」
Well, this is just an ideal story, though ^^;
さて、今日も始めましょうか…
Well, shall we begin today as well...
あ～！またやっちゃった～！
Ah! I did it again!
実際はご覧の通り まだまだ未熟な見習いなんです
Actually, as you can see, I'm still just an inexperienced apprentice
先人に憧れ持って 私も！と飛び込んだものの
Admiring my predecessors, I dove in too, but...
現実はそんな簡単に上手くいかないなあ…
Reality isn't that easy to get right...
「怪奇模した喜劇が幕開け 一目見ればたちまち虜に！？」
"A comedy mimicking the strange begins. One look and you'll be captivated!?"
え？既にそれさっき見た？なら、飽き性なあなたにも【朗報】
Eh? You already saw that? Then, here's good news for the fickle you.
Q.ちょっと前の模倣をするだけ
Q. Just imitating the recent past?
A.繰り返しじゃつまらない！
A. Repetition is boring!
だから、ここから先は趣向を変えてみよう！
So, from here on, let's change things up!
ドタバタなサーカスの行方は 誰にも自分すらも分からない！？
The fate of this slapstick circus... no one, not even I, knows!?
私を選んだ君だけでも楽しんでってよ～～～！！！
At least you, who chose me, please enjoy it!!!
損させないから
I won't let you down.
いつの日か皆と楽しめるショーがしたいんだよな～！
Someday, I want to perform a show everyone can enjoy!
だからこそ、こんなところで挫けるわけとかな～い！
That's why there's no way I'm giving up here!
言葉なんかじゃ言い表せない あの感動を私もいつか…
Someday, I too... that emotion beyond words...
とても偉大なこのステージに 見合っているか分かんないけれど
I don't know if I'm worthy of this great stage, but...
観客全て、私の色で染め尽くしてやろう！
I'll paint every single member of the audience in my color!
手始めに、今、眼の前の君たちからいくよ～～～！！！
To start, I'm coming for all of you right here!!!
創造しよう
Let's create.
華々しいスポットライトの中
Under the brilliant spotlight,
目を奪うような妙技の数々
Countless breathtaking feats.
この空間が世界で一番 “娯楽”の名に相応しいんだ！
This space is the most worthy of the name "entertainment" in the world!
割れんばかりの歓声と拍手でショーが終わっていく
The show ends amidst thunderous cheers and applause.
ああ…これが私が望んだ夢のエンディング。
Ah... this is the dream ending I wished for.
これは花の国のお姫様がこの王国へいらっしゃった時のお話。
This is a story from when a princess from the Flower Kingdom came to this kingdom.
まだみんな彼女の事を知らない頃だったので
It was a time when no one knew who she was yet,
国民の大半は、アホの子なんて言ってたけど、
so most of the citizens called her a "silly girl," but,
とっても心優しくそして気さくで頼りになるお姫様だったんだよ。
she was a very kind, friendly, and reliable princess.
なんたって、みこはお姫様なんだから！
After all, Miko is a princess!
女神！ 聖女！
Goddess! Saint!
叡智！ 聡明！ 慈愛！ 博愛！
Wisdom! Intelligence! Benevolence! Philanthropy!
あたし なんたってお姫様
After all, I'm a princess
この人生におけるヒロイン ですわー！
The heroine of this life. Desu wa-!
一生姫でイージーモード！って思ったら勝手にどうぞ！？
Thinking life's easy mode as a lifelong princess? Suit yourself!?
世間はいっつも風向き次第
The world is always changing like the wind
有象無象ばかりでホント、人間不信になっちゃう
Honestly, surrounded by such rabble, I'm losing faith in humanity
気付いたのこの世界に血も涙もないこと
I realized there's no blood or tears in this world
あれもダメ これもダメ それもダメ どれもダメ
That's no good, this is no good, that's no good, everything's no good
現実（リアル）は世知辛い
Reality is a harsh world
全部改変ですわ…！
I'll alter it all...!
あたし なんたってお姫様
After all, I'm a princess
この人生におけるヒロイン
The heroine of this life
悲しいシナリオも全部全部 書き換えちゃうの
I'll rewrite every single sad scenario
だってだってお姫様
Because, after all, I'm a princess
自分の物語くらいは
At least my own story...
キラキラ楽しまなきゃ ですわ！ですわ！ですわ！
...has to be sparkling and fun. Desu wa! Desu wa! Desu wa!
今に見てなさい！運命なんて改変して差し上げますわ！
Just you wait! I'll go ahead and alter destiny itself for you!
だれ？だれ？だれ？だれ？裏で糸を引いてるのはだれ？
Who? Who? Who? Who? Who's pulling the strings from behind?
操り人形だなんてごめんだわ まったく
I'm not going to be anyone's puppet, seriously
上品な顔してても 黒幕はあの人かも！？
Even with that elegant face, that person might be the mastermind!?
まずはあたしが強くならなきゃ 未来は変わらない
First, I have to become strong, or the future won't change
改革だ…
It's a revolution...
自分改革ですわ…！
A self-revolution...!
そうよ なんたってお姫様
That's right, after all I'm a princess
あたしこそ最高の権力者
I'm the one with the ultimate power
生涯すべての主導権はこちらにあるわ
I hold the initiative for my entire life
だってだってお姫様 自分で決めたことくらいは
Because, after all, I'm a princess. At least my own decisions...
わがままに行かなきゃ
I've got to go my own selfish way
ですわ！ですわ！ですわ！
I shall! I shall! I shall!
女神！
Goddess!
聖女！
Saint!
叡智！
Wisdom!
聡明！
Intelligence!
慈愛！
Benevolence!
博愛！
Philanthropy!
天才ですわ！
I'm a genius!
今日も軽くステップする
Stepping lightly again today
運命の歯車が踊り出す
The gears of fate begin to dance
顔を上げたその時
The moment I looked up
ほら世界が恋をする
Look, the world falls in love
あたしハッピーエンドプリンセス
I'm a Happy End Princess
この人生におけるヒロイン
The heroine of this life
すったもんだある日々も
Even through the ups and downs
全部全部愛してみせるの
I'll show you I can love every bit of it
ハッピーエンドプリンセス
Happy End Princess
自分の物語くらいは
At least in my own story
キラキラ楽しまなきゃ
I've got to enjoy it sparklingly
ですわ！ですわ！ですわ！
I shall! I shall! I shall!
全力で生き抜かなきゃ
I've got to live through it with all I've got
ですわ！ですわ！ですわ！
I shall! I shall! I shall!
今にみてなさい！
Just you wait and see!
運命なんて
Something like fate...
改変して差し上げますわ！
...I shall rewrite it for you!
女神！
Goddess!
聖女！
Saint!
叡智！
Wisdom!
聡明！
Intelligence!
慈愛！
Benevolence!
博愛！
Philanthropy!
ですわ！
I shall!
王国で一躍有名になった小説の１つじゃないか
Isn't that one of those novels that suddenly became famous in the kingdom?
…ある女子学生探偵と推理作家の先生が織りなす楽しい…え？
...A fun story woven by a certain schoolgirl detective and a mystery writer... eh?
いやいや、この事件が実際にあったのかまではわからないよ、
No, no, we don't know if this case actually happened,
でも、このシリーズは凄く人気なんですよね。
but this series is incredibly popular, isn't it.
わかりました！犯人はあなたですね！
I've got it! The culprit is you!
名探偵連続殺人事件
作詞・作曲：てにをは
Detective Continuous Murder Case
Lyrics & Composition: Teniwoha
あ、あ、赤い密室ストーリーライン
A-a-a-red locked-room storyline
七つ道具はしまっちゃえ
Pack away your seven tools
アクロイド殺された探偵が
The detective who was murdered like Ackroyd
また一人姿を消したという
is said to have vanished once again.
綾なす辻のアリスがわ
The Alice of the weaving crossroads
横溝掃除は江戸川か
Is it Yokomizo cleaning or Edogawa?
神田最弱探偵さん
The weakest detective in Kanda
こんなんどう居ると思う
How do you think something like this exists?
ナンマンダブしてステップ踏み
Chanting 'Namman-dabu' and taking a step
脳髄これ密室なりや
Is the brain itself a locked room?
グッドバイで会った人、グッドバイで別れましょう
Let's part with a goodbye, to the one met with a goodbye
謎解きはこれから ラ・ラ・ラ・ラ
The mystery solving begins now, la la la la
「犯人はあなたですね」
"The culprit is you"
列車トリック薄荷トリック難事件
Train trick, mint trick, a difficult case
推理作家の先生さん あははは
The mystery writer, ahahaha
うだるさだる うだるさだる 今にみておれ
Sweltering heat, sweltering heat, just you wait and see
あぁもう 頭がこんがらがってきたけれど
Ah, jeez, my head is starting to get all tangled up, but...
どとはらい どっとこむ あっちゃんちゃぱりぱり
Doto-harai dot com, ac-chan-cha pari pari
エブリバディわんこそば
Everybody Wanko Soba
「謎はおやつに入りません」
"Mysteries don't count as snacks"
どとはらい どっとこむ あっちゃんちゃ どんしゃりどんしゃり
Doto-harai dot com, ac-chan-cha don-shari don-shari
エブリバディあーいーばーいーなーいーなーいーなーい
Everybody eye-bye-night-night-night-night
エセエセライヘンバッハガラスなき
Fake fake Reichenbach, without any glass
番台三寸付いてご清聴
Three inches from the counter, thank you for listening
オリエント急行客車の窓
The window of a carriage on the Orient Express
あの怪盗たちがまくという
that those phantom thieves are said to be sowing.
高木に二人海の原
Two in a tall tree, the vast sea
坂口安吾無視したろう
You ignored Sakaguchi Ango, didn't you?
ABCだかエビスだか
Whether it's the ABCs or Ebisu
レモンドちゃんとシケ
Lemond-chan and a dead end
甲が乙をかくす
A hides B
そんじゃ降参降参さんお疲れさん
Then, surrender, surrender-san, good job
四捨五入やってみな、死者五人どこ行った
Try rounding off... where did the five dead people go?
謎解きはまだまだだだだだ
The mystery solving is still far from over...
「そして誰もいなくなった？」
"And then there were none?"
およしになっておやめになって怪事件
Please stop, please end this mysterious case
おさげ揺らす探偵さん
The detective shaking their braids
レックスべべガスコンべべ行かないで
Rex-bebe Gascon-bebe, don't go
あぁもう先生の意地悪わがままいどとはらい
Ah, jeez, teacher's mean selfishness, doto-harai...
どとはらい どっとこむ あっちゃんちゃぱりぱり
Doto-harai dot com, ac-chan-cha pari pari
エブリバディわんこそば
Everybody Wanko Soba
「たまには自分で考えたまえ」
"Try thinking for yourself for once"
どとはらい どっとこむ あっちゃんちゃ どんしゃりどんしゃり
Doto-harai dot com, ac-chan-cha don-shari don-shari
Everybody
アリバイ
Alibi
ない、ない、ない
None, none, none
怪盗レムの罠にはまり、次々と姿を消していく名探偵たち。
Falling into Phantom Thief Rem's trap, the famous detectives disappear one after another.
そして探偵のいぬ間に、人々の心は密室となった。
And while the detectives were away, people's hearts became locked rooms.
でも、それならどうして私だけが無事だったんでしょうか？
But if so, why was I the only one safe?
その答えはひとつしか考えられない。
There can only be one answer to that.
と、いうと……？
Which is...?
あまりに無能すぎるがゆえに、君は探偵として勘定にも入れられていなかったのだ！
Because you're so incompetent, you weren't even counted as a detective!
ひどーい！
That's mean!
およしになって　おやめになって　怪奇事件
Please stop, please quit this mysterious incident
おさげ揺らす探偵さん
The detective with swinging braids
Knock's Baby, God's Done Baby, いかないで
Knock's Baby, God's Done Baby, don't go
And more　先生のいじわるイケズ
And more, Professor's mean trick
レトロなトリック　ハットトリック　難事件
Retro trick, hat trick, difficult case
推理作家の先生
Professor, the mystery writer
うだらぱだら　うだらぱだら　言わないで
Don't say "udara-padara udara-padara"
あぁもう　頭がこんがらがってきたけど
Ah, my head is getting all tangled up
可愛い可愛いや　トリック甘いね　通りゃんせ
Cute, so cute, your tricks are naive, please pass through
小さい二人の子供が約束した。
Two small children made a promise.
ずっといっしょに笑っていようの約束。
A promise to keep laughing together forever.
今もなお、二人の絆は確かなもので、
Even now, the bond between them is certain,
友情と愛情が織りなす素敵な物語。
A wonderful story woven from friendship and love.
あははっ……なんでもないことに、妙にツボっちゃう時あるよねっ。
Ahaha... There are times when you just get a weird fit of giggles over nothing, right?
あー恋に落ちたまゆら
Ah, a fleeting moment of falling in love
開花止まらないや
The blooming doesn't stop
何度も捲って
Turning the pages over and over
心をかし
Lending my heart
泣いてばっかだったの　それがどうだい今や
I used to do nothing but cry, but look at me now
腹捩れるくらい笑う
I laugh until my sides ache
ずっと一緒に笑う
We'll laugh together forever
きみが持ってる白い花に
Against the white flower you hold
あたし見合わないかな　悲しくなる
I might not be worthy, it makes me sad
無垢な恋とか正しさとか
Innocent love and righteousness
誰も教えてくれなかった
No one ever taught me about them
昨日会ったばっかで
We only met yesterday
今日もどっか会えたら　なんて思う暮らし
Hoping to meet somewhere again today
慎ましくないよね　全部許されたの
It's not very modest, is it? Everything was forgiven
びっくりしちゃってさ　涙あふれてたよ
I was so surprised, tears started overflowing
もう愛になる鼻歌
A hum that's turning into love
透き通った空に　手を繋いでいった　夢のしるし
Under the clear sky, holding hands, a sign of a dream
どんな前世だってさ　忘れたっていいんだ
Whatever our past lives were, it's okay to forget
きみと笑えるなら
As long as I can laugh with you
心が触れるたび　綺麗な音鳴る
Every time our hearts touch, a beautiful sound rings out
目と目が合ってくすぐったいね
When our eyes meet, it feels so ticklish
なんでもないこと　妙にツボるね
The simplest things make us burst into giggles
全部教えてくれて　ありがとう
Thank you for teaching me everything
きみが持ってる白い花を
The white flower you hold
あたしの紅色と合わせたら
If I combine it with my crimson color
霜が解けては雲が行く
The frost thaws and the clouds pass by
もう寒くないよ
It's not cold anymore
あー恋に落ちたまゆら
Ah, a fleeting moment of falling in love
開花止まらないや
The blooming doesn't stop
何度も捲って　心をかし
Turning the pages over and over, lending my heart
泣いてばっかだったの　それがどうだい今や
I used to do nothing but cry, but look at me now
腹捩れるくらい笑う
I laugh until my sides ache
ずっと一緒に笑って
Keep laughing together forever
（恋に落ちたまゆら）
(A fleeting moment of falling in love)
（心をかし）
(Lending my heart)
（愛になる鼻歌）
(A hum that's turning into love)
（ずっと一緒に笑う）
(Laughing together forever)
最後の日を笑う
Laugh on the final day
これは、遠い遠い名も知らぬ世界で、
This is, in a far, far unknown world...
死の呪いがかけられた少女のお話
A story of a girl who was cursed with death
林檎売りの泡沫少女
The Bubble Girl who Sells Apples
遠い遠い時の果て
At the end of a long, long time
そこに住まう人は皆
Everyone living there
永遠の命を持つ
Has eternal life
世界での話
In a world of legend
赤い実の成る木の下
Beneath a tree bearing red fruit
La La Lu La 生まれながらに
La La Lu La, from the moment she was born
死の呪いがかけられた
She was cursed with death
少女の話
The story of that girl
色付いた街外れ
On the colorful outskirts of town
蒼く光る湖畔
By the blue, glowing lakeside
赤い実のお菓子屋
A sweets shop of red fruit
ちょっぴり寒くなった
It's gotten a little colder
今日は妙に誇らしげ
Today she feels strangely proud
自信作を売りにゆく
Going to sell her masterpiece
待ってて 今度こそ
Wait for me, this time for sure
美味しいんだから
I know it will be delicious
時計塔の見える市
A market within sight of the clock tower
驚いたね珍しく
What a surprise, unusually
賑やかなね La La Lu La Lucky!!
It's so lively, La La Lu La Lucky!!
物憂げな街の隅
In a melancholy corner of town
独り赤い実のパイ
All alone with a red fruit pie
どうですか 自信作なの
How about it? It's my masterpiece
そんなの
Something like that
ひと口も売れないさ
Won't even sell a single bite
少女を見て蔑む人達
People look at the girl with disdain
誰一人と変わりないのに
Even though she's no different from anyone else
美味しくできたのに
Even though it turned out delicious
今日も声は届かないのね
Again today, her voice doesn't reach
まるで透明になったみたいだわ
It's as if I've become invisible
そうして誰もが知らぬふりをした
And so everyone pretended not to notice
何故なら少女は呪われているから
Because the girl is cursed
死んだ世界でただ独り生きていた
Living all alone in a dead world
少女の話
The story of that girl
夜なべでアレンジパイとにっこりスマイル引っさげ
With an improved pie made overnight and a sunny smile
少女はまた諦めない
The girl won't give up yet
時計塔の針も空を指してお腹も鳴る
The clock hands point at the sky as her stomach growls
そんな時
Just then
ふと後ろから
Suddenly from behind
人が少女を押す
Someone pushes the girl
甘い籠は落ちる
And the basket of sweets falls
お菓子を踏み行く人達
People walk by, stepping on the treats
平気な顔をしてさ
With indifferent faces
惨めに拾い集める
She miserably gathers them up
ふともう独りの手が
When suddenly, another hand reaches out
ドロドロのパイを 脆く口に入れて
Putting a piece of the muddy pie into his mouth
「美味しいね」
"It's delicious"
その声で心は溢れた
With those words, her heart overflowed
まるで輪郭を描いたみたいだわ
It's as if I've found my silhouette
そうして彼は手を差し出した
And so he reached out his hand
何故なら少女に呪われているから
Because he is cursed by the girl
死んだ世界で運命のふたり生きていた
Two people of destiny living in a dead world
遠い物語
A distant story
街の人達は哀れむ
The people of the town pity them
赤い実を食べて呪われた者を
Those cursed for eating the red fruit
永遠に生きられずに死ぬのさ
They'll die without being able to live forever
なんて可哀想な話
What a tragic story, they say
ふたりは笑う
The two of them laugh
それでも笑う
Even so, they laugh
La La La とっても素敵な呪いね
La La La, it's a truly wonderful curse
たとえ明日死んでも
Even if we die tomorrow
「今」が確かで
The "now" is real
大切になるから
And will become precious to us
もう声は届かないのね
The voice doesn't reach anymore, does it?
まるで透明になったみたいだわ
It's as if I've become invisible
そうして誰もが知らぬふりをした
And so everyone pretended not to notice
何故なら世界が呪われているから
Because it is the world that is cursed
『永遠』の呪いは解けていた
The curse of "eternity" was broken
まるでふたりの方が狂ったみたいだろう
It probably seems as if the two of them are the ones who are mad
そしていつか笑うように眠る
And so, one day, sleep as if smiling
なぜならフタリは放たれているから
Because the two of us have been set free
死んだ世界でただフタリだけが幸せだった...
In a dead world, only the two of us were happy...
さて、今日はこれくらいにしておきましょう。
Now then, let's call it a day for today.
…そろそろ時間になりましたし
...it's about time.
え？どこへ向かうのかって？
Eh? Where are we headed?
今日は何の日かご存知ないのですか？
Do you not know what day it is today?
今日は、この王国の地下深くにある冥界でのハロウィンパーティーですよ！
Today is the Halloween party in the underworld, deep beneath this kingdom!
死者と生者が楽しむ年に一度のお祭りです。
It's a once-a-year festival enjoyed by the dead and the living.
さあ、一緒に向かいましょう。
Now, let's go together.
でも、気をつけて。
But, be careful.
パーティーとは言え、死者が住まう冥界です。
Even if it's a party, it's the underworld where the dead reside.
誰かの思念や死者たちによって奇妙な事が起こるかもしれません、
Strange things might happen due to someone's thoughts or the dead,
でも、決してそちらに耳を傾けすぎてはいけませんよ…
but you must never listen to them too closely...
それでは、参りましょう
Well then, let's go.
蒼炎
Souen (Blue Flame)
作詞・作曲：ル乃
Lyrics & Composition: Luno
誰かが言いました
Someone once said
激しく燃えるものほど
the more fiercely something burns,
煌めく引き換えに
in exchange for its brilliance,
その身をすぐ焦がしきると
it soon scorches itself away.
数ある燭台に
Upon numerous candlesticks,
お好きな火を灯しましょう
let us light the flames you desire.
期待と裏腹に
Contrary to expectations,
燻ればお生憎様
if it merely smolders, how unfortunate.
ランランランラン
Ran ran ran ran
右手には錆びた時計
In my right hand, a rusted clock.
ランランランラン
Ran ran ran ran
左には油の筒
In my left, a cylinder of oil.
ランランランラン
Ran ran ran ran
繻子のドレスを着飾って　さあ
Dressed up in a satin dress, now...
激しく　儚く
Fiercely, fleetingly,
蒼く燃ゆる花びら
Blue-burning petals.
瞬き　ゆらめく
Twinkling, flickering,
生を彩り照らせ
Lighting up and coloring life.
いずれ尽き果てる未来へと
Toward a future that will eventually run out.
ゆりかごの目の前で
Before the cradle,
数多飛び交う銃弾
Numerous bullets flying about.
指だけ動かせば　容易くその火は潰える
With just a flick of a finger, that flame easily vanishes.
仮初の情熱で
With a fleeting passion,
灼けただれた舌では
with a tongue scorched and raw,
上手に喋ることができないようで
it seems you cannot speak properly.
喉元過ぎても毒を孕ませて
Even after it passes the throat, let the poison fester,
やがては肺を腐らせる
eventually rotting the lungs.
…やがては腑を腐らせるでしょう
...it will eventually rot your guts.
ランランランラン
Ran ran ran ran
揺らぐ死と生の端
In the gap between flickering life and death
焦げる心と歌う
I sing with a burning heart
描いた最愛の終幕を
The beloved ending I envisioned
激しく 儚く 青く燃ゆる花びら
Intense and fleeting, petals burning blue
瞬き ゆらめく 生を彩り照らせ
Twinkling and flickering, illuminate and color life
いずれ尽き果てるその先へ
Towards what lies beyond the eventual end
あちらの世界に引きずり込まれないうちに早く会場へ向かわないといけませんね。
We have to hurry to the venue before we're dragged into that world.
気を付けてついてきてくださいね。
Please follow me carefully.
あまり深入りすると、おっと…
If you go too deep, oops...
そうそう、知らないほうがきっと懸命ですよ。
Exactly, it's probably wiser not to know.
なんだか、すっごく心地が良いよね。
It feels really good somehow.
気付けば見知らぬ世界に立っていた
Before I knew it, I was standing in an unknown world
何処かも分からず毎日毎日泣いていた
Not knowing where I was, I cried every single day
なんて暇もなく
Without a moment to spare
Happy Time おかしな面々が
Happy Time, strange characters
Happy Time おどけて転がるの
Happy Time, clowning and rolling around
その馬鹿馬鹿しさに希望も恐怖もなくなった
In that absurdity, both hope and fear vanished
確かそうアタシには為すべき仕事
That's right, I have work to do
愛の棲家 パンプキン ヘッドギア
Abode of love, pumpkin, headgear
だけどなんかどーでもいい
But somehow, I don't care anymore
さぁ始まった 夢の夜だ
Now it's begun, the night of dreams
音楽が響いて鳴り止まない
Music echoes and won't stop
声を揃えて叫べ今日は
Raise your voices and scream today
Amazing Happy Halloween Night!
ジャック いたずら 無礼講だ
Jack-o'-lantern, pranks, no holds barred
真面目に生きても割に合わない
Living seriously isn't worth it
なんでもありさ 何故って今日は
Anything goes, because today is
Amazing Happy Halloween Night!
消えちゃった 消えちゃった 出口はないんだって そう永遠に
Gone, gone, there's no exit, yes, forever
消えちゃった 消えちゃった 思想 ルール 倫理 関係ない
Gone, gone, thoughts, rules, ethics, they don't matter
Amazing Happy Halloween Night!
「私はロボットではありません」に
To "I am not a robot"
無心でチェックし解答するけれど
I mindlessly check and answer, but
本当にそうかな
Is that really true?
Happy Life とりま音に乗せて
Happy Life, just riding the sound for now
Happy Life デタラメに踊るの
Happy Life, dancing randomly
その繰り返しのなか懐疑心も失った
In those repetitions, I even lost my skepticism
意思のない様まるでロボトミーした電気羊
Will-less, like a lobotomized electric sheep
ナイトメア NPC
Nightmare NPC
だけどなんか心地がいい
But somehow it feels good
おっと音声が乱れました
Oops, the audio got distorted
お気になさらずに皆々様
Please don't mind it, everyone
そんなお口は縫い合わせて
Sew up those mouths
Amazing Happy Halloween Night!
良い子の口にはチョコとキャンディ
Chocolate and candy for the mouths of good children
歯に衣着せちゃ噛み合わない
If you mince your words, they won't mesh
気を取り直し皆でどうぞ
Pull yourselves together and everyone, if you please
Amazing Happy Halloween Night!
知っちゃった 知っちゃった
I found out, I found out
全部全部理解した
I understood everything, everything
だから何も見たくねえわ
So I don't want to see anything
さぁ始まった 夢の夜だ
Now it's begun, the night of dreams
音楽が響いて鳴り止まない
Music echoes and won't stop
声を揃えて叫べ今日は
Raise your voices and scream today
Amazing Happy Halloween Night!
ジャック いたずら 無礼講だ
Jack-o'-lantern, pranks, no holds barred
真面目に生きても割に合わない
Living seriously isn't worth it
なんでもありさ 何故って今日は
Anything goes, because today is
Amazing Happy Halloween Night!
泣いちゃった 泣いちゃった 知らないほうがきっと懸命ね
I cried, I cried, it's probably wiser not to know
泣いちゃった 泣いちゃった このパーティーに終わりはない
I cried, I cried, this party will never end
Amazing Happy Halloween Night!
トリック・オア・トリート！
Trick or Treat!
お菓子をくれても
Even if you give me sweets...
イタズラはしちゃうよ！
...I'll still play a trick!
狂笑トリックスターズ
作詞・作曲：OSTER project
Mad Laughter Tricksters
Lyrics/Composition: OSTER project
ようこそ everyone みのけもよだつこの spooky night
Welcome everyone to this hair-raising spooky night
腹の底まで揺れ kick & bass & hats & trumpet
Shake to the bottom of your gut with kick, bass, hats, & trumpet
ランタンと swingin' beat 赤い靴で踊り狂えば
With lanterns and a swingin' beat, if you dance madly in red shoes
浮世の煩いも忘れられるでしょ
You'll surely forget the troubles of this fleeting world
地も泥も巷じゃお化けよりも怖い人たち
The people in the streets are scarier than ghosts
怯えさせちゃってすぐに 1 out, 2 out, 3 out, knockout
Making them tremble, it's 1 out, 2 out, 3 out, knockout
コンプライアンスも厳しい世の中ですが
Even in this world where compliance is so strict
恐怖のリライト請け負います
We'll take on the rewriting of your fears
Give me a cherry pie それとも may I choke you up?
Give me a cherry pie, or may I choke you up?
Give me a flowy dress それとも may I stab you to death?
Give me a flowy dress, or may I stab you to death?
Poison, rope, hot and cake, knife, scissors, lovely flake
Choose one...
「さぁ選んで」
"Now, choose."
なんちゃってドッキリ大成功
Just kidding! Prank successful!
響くパンパカパンパンファンファーレで
With a resounding fanfare of 'pan-paka-pan-pan'
にっこり笑っちゃってハイポーズ
Give a big smile and say 'Hi, pose!'
あー怖かったなんて
Saying 'Ah, that was scary'
座り込んで涙目で
While sitting down with teary eyes
笑う顔見たいな
I want to see your laughing face
ちっちゃな箱の中のモンスターに怯えるくらいなら
If you're going to be scared of monsters in a little box
いつだってここにおいで
Come here anytime
もっとずっと本能的に楽しくなれる
You can have much more instinctive fun
恐怖と踊っちゃおうぜ
Let's dance with our fears
走想電移でキマってカタルシス
Get high on catharsis through runaway thoughts
もう一丁ジェットコースターでごきげんデトックス
One more time, a cheery detox on a roller coaster
満月が暴く醜悪な本性
The full moon exposes an ugly true nature
デタラメに杖振り回し hocus pocus
Waving a wand randomly, hocus pocus
劣等感を隠れ蓑に育つ呪いを
Do you know how to pluck the curse
摘み取る術を知ってるかい？
That grows under the cloak of inferiority?
「迷える哀れな仔羊たちよ」
"O pitiful, lost little lambs,"
「お菓子が欲しいかい？それとも安らぎが欲しいかい？」
"Do you want candy? Or do you want peace?"
「永遠に求め続けるの？」
"Will you keep seeking it forever?"
「それならば、ずっと苦しいままだ」
"If so, you will remain in pain forever."
「恐怖からの解放によって、」
"If there is salvation to be achieved"
「成し得る救済があるのならば」
"by being released from fear,"
「この目隠しはそのままに」
"then let this blindfold remain."
「さぁ、イタズラ完了」
"Now, the trick is complete."
永遠に断ち切れない呪いの鎖に囚われ
Imprisoned by the chains of an unbreakable curse
朽ち果ててしまう前に
Before you completely rot away
脳みそちょっといじるだけであら不思議
Just a little tweak to the brain, and oh wonder
こんなに気持ち良くて気分爽快
It feels so good, it's totally refreshing
なんちゃってドッキリ大成功
Just kidding! Prank successful!
響くパンパカパンパンファンファーレで
With a resounding fanfare of 'pan-paka-pan-pan'
にっこり笑っちゃってハイポーズ
Give a big smile and say 'Hi, pose!'
あー怖かったなんて
Saying 'Ah, that was scary'
へたり込んで涙目で
While slumping down with teary eyes
笑う顔いいな
I like that laughing face
もう苦しまなくていいよ こんなに頑張ったんだから
You don't have to suffer anymore, you've worked so hard
躊躇わずこっちにおいで
Don't hesitate, come this way
もうずっと本能的に気持ちいいだけの
I'll show you the goal
ゴールを見せてあげる
That's nothing but instinctive pleasure
混急急案でこそ光るカタルシス
Catharsis shines through in urgent cases
もう一丁全リセットで魂デトックス
One more time, a soul detox with a total reset
いつかの、あったかもしれない世界の出来事までも、
Even the events of a world that might have once been...
この冥界ではこうして思念として漂っているんだね。
...are floating here in this underworld as thoughts.
あまり深入りしてはいけないよ、こういうのが一番質が悪い。
Don't delve too deep. This kind of thing is the most troublesome.
私はただ、あなたを愛していただけ。
I simply loved you.
物言わぬ唇に生気を吹き込んで、
Breathing life into silent lips,
今宵「あなた」は甦る、
Tonight, "you" shall be reborn,
あの頃の姿で。
as you were back then.
ネクロの花嫁
作詞・作曲：奏音69
The Necro-Bride
Lyrics/Composition: Kanon69
白肌の娘が残した。
The white-skinned girl left a message.
「この身体貴方に捧げるわ」
"I offer this body to you."
白服の医者が囁いた。
A doctor in white whispered,
「迎えに行くよ」
"I'm coming for you."
白肌の娘は朽ち果てた
世界の誰にも見捨てられ
The white-skinned girl withered away,
abandoned by everyone in the world.
白服の医者は憐れんで、
誰も知らない居場所で眠らせた
The doctor in white took pity and laid
her to rest in a place known to no one.
朽ちてもまだ 美しい顔で、
Even in decay, with that beautiful face,
ふたりしかいない霊廟で、医者は恋をした。
In the mausoleum where they were alone,
the doctor fell in love.
それは永遠の恋か。
Was it eternal love?
禁断の行為か。
Or a forbidden act?
また逢いたいと願うだけ。
Just wishing to meet again...
それが罪なのでしょうか。
...is that a sin?
物謂わぬ唇に
Into those silent lips,
生気を吹き込んで、
breathing life,
今宵ふたりは結ばれる。
Tonight, the two shall be joined.
祝福もされずに。
Without any blessing.
塞ぎこんだ眼窩に青い硝子を
Blue glass for the hollow eye sockets,
破れかけた腕に絹の薔薇を
silk roses for the tattered arms,
侵された内臓に綿のガーゼを
cotton gauze for the ravaged organs,
宝石で飾った白いドレス
and a white dress adorned with jewels.
朽ちゆくたび
Every time she decayed,
取り繕って、
mending her,
恋を謳って、
singing of love,
また医者は
the doctor
手を染め続けた。
continued to stain his hands.
やがて暴かれたのは
Eventually, what was exposed
醜い怪物で、
was a hideous monster,
それを作り上げた医者は
and the doctor who created it
辨駁を叫んだ。
cried out his defense.
「これは永遠の恋だ。
"This is eternal love.
彼女の願望だ。
This is her wish.
死にゆくと決めたお前らが
Isn't she the woman you all abandoned
見捨てた女じゃないか」
when you left her to die?"
嗚呼......哀しき花嫁。
Ah... the sorrowful bride.
物謂えぬままで、
Unable to speak,
今宵ふたりは裁かれる。
tonight, the two will be judged.
彼女を見捨てた人達の正義で。
By the justice of the people
who abandoned her.
正しいのはだあれ？
Who is the righteous one?
さて、ハロウィンパーティーもついにフィナーレ。
Now, the Halloween party has finally reached its finale.
ここでご参加くださった国民の皆様へ
冥界からのお土産品のご紹介です。
I'd like to introduce some underworld souvenirs
to the citizens who joined us.
お土産品は全4種類。
There are four types of souvenirs in total.
フルセットでご購入いただいた皆様には
特典もございます。
Special bonuses are included for
those who purchase the full set.
ご一緒に詳しく見ていきましょう。
Let's take a closer look together.
まず1つ目。今回の冥界ハロウィンナイトを
イメージした ワイドラバーマットです。
First up is a wide rubber mat themed
after this Underworld Halloween Night.
国王様の横には 冥界の女王の姿が。
Beside the King is the Queen of the Underworld.
名を、ナイラというそうです。
Her name is apparently Naira.
冥界のハロウィンを存分に楽しんでほしいと
いう気持ちを込めた 彼女のイメージソングも
Her image song, filled with wishes for
you to enjoy the underworld's Halloween,
この後お披露目予定なので、 お楽しみに。
...is scheduled to be debuted soon,
so please look forward to it.
素敵なイラストは Matcha様に
描いていただきました。
The wonderful illustration was
drawn by Matcha-sama.
2つ目は パスポート風王国シール帳です。
Second is the passport-style Kingdom sticker book.
このシール帳には これからたくさんの
思い出を記していきたいですね。
I hope to fill this sticker book with
many memories from now on.
王国の軌跡として 国民の皆様も今後
集めてみてはいかがでしょうか。
Why don't you citizens collect them too,
as a chronicle of the Kingdom?
その一歩として 今回のキービジュアルの
ステッカーを1枚 封入しております。
As a first step, a sticker of this time's
key visual is included.
3つ目は SUKONBU FACTORYより
キングフブちゃんぬいぐるみです。
Third, the King Fubu-chan plushie
from SUKONBU FACTORY.
こちらは国王自らデザインをしており
とても愛らしいぬいぐるみとなっております。
This was designed by the King himself
and is a very adorable plushie.
前回のボリューム1のぬいぐるみをお持ちの方は
ご一緒に飾ってあげてくださいね。
If you have the Volume 1 plushie,
please display them together.
4つ目は 王国リボンチャームです。
Fourth is the Kingdom ribbon charm.
こちらは秘書である私の胸元のリボンが
再現されております。
This reproduces the ribbon from
my chest, as the secretary.
カバンにつけたり...
You can attach it to your bag...
…もよし
...is fine,
ペンライトに付けるもよしと
and attaching it to a penlight is also fine.
多機能なリボンチャームとなっておりますので
Since it's a multi-functional ribbon charm,
皆様の「推し活」とやらにぜひご活用ください
please use it for your 'oshi-katsu' and such.
最後は特典のお知らせです
Finally, an announcement regarding the bonus.
フルセットをご購入の方全員にチェキ風ブロマイドカードを１つお付けいたします
Everyone who purchases the full set will receive one Cheki-style bromide card.
複製サインと国王からのメッセージもあるそうですよ
It seems there's a reproduced signature and a message from the King.
数量限定バージョンは直筆サイン入りですので皆様お早めに
The limited edition version is hand-signed, so please be quick, everyone.
以上、今回のお土産品紹介でした
That's all for the merchandise introduction this time.
さて、この後は冥界の女王様をイメージした楽曲
Now, next is a song inspired by the Queen of the Underworld,
「冥界Halloween Night!」のお披露目です
the premiere of 'Underworld Halloween Night!'
楽しまれた後は、無事王国へお帰りくださいね
After you've enjoyed it, please return safely to the Kingdom.
それでは
And now...
Welcome!
さあ、踊ろうよ
Come on, let's dance
This is Halloween Night!
冥界Halloween Night!
作詞・作曲・編曲：中野領太、野口大志
Underworld Halloween Night!
Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: Ryota Nakano, Taishi Noguchi
冥界を挙げてのParty (Party)
A party involving the whole underworld (Party)
ルール違反はダメですよ Warning (Warning)
Breaking the rules is not allowed, Warning (Warning)
説明は一度きり (Only)
The explanation is only once (Only)
聞き逃せばあの世行き
If you miss it, you're going to the next world
冗談ですよ
Just kidding
(い！) お菓子を持って
(1!) Bring some treats
(に！) 仮装して集まって！
(2!) Dress up and gather!
生か死か死か生かは隠す事
Whether life or death, death or life, keep it hidden
(よん！) いつだって強気で
(4!) Always be confident
(ご！) 油断禁物です
(5!) Don't let your guard down
最後の最後はご無事で帰ること
And in the very end, return safely
一人きりじゃつまらないわ
It's no fun being all alone
この退屈な城の玉座で
On the throne of this boring castle
指をずっと待ちわびてた
I've been waiting for a long time
人恋しいとか？
Are you lonely for people?
やだ！そんなんじゃないってば！
No! I told you it's not like that!
Let's 冥界Halloween Night!
Let's Meikai Halloween Night!
Dancing! Dancing! 陽気にハッピーなメロディー
Dancing! Dancing! A cheerful and happy melody
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ 冥界Halloween Night!
Rat-ta-ta, Rat-ta-ta, Meikai Halloween Night!
Swinging! Swinging! ゾッとして愉快なアイロニー
Swinging! Swinging! A spine-chilling and pleasant irony
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ 狂騒のショータイム
Rat-ta-ta, Rat-ta-ta, A rowdy showtime
(Pa Pa Pa) 恐ろしいな
(Pa Pa Pa) How scary
(Pu Pu Pu) 恨めしいな
(Pu Pu Pu) How resentful
夢も重さも忘れてる
Forgetting both dreams and weight
おろろ？
Oh?
(Pa Pa Pa) 美味しそうな
(Pa Pa Pa) Looks delicious
(Pu Pu Pu) 魂だわ
(Pu Pu Pu) What a soul
Welcome! さあ、踊ろうよ This is Halloween Night!
Welcome! Come on, let's dance, This is Halloween Night!
響くガタガタなTuning (Tuning)
The rattling tuning (Tuning) echoes
その不協和音さえもMusic (Music)
Even that dissonance is music (Music)
王室のドアが開き (開き)
The royal door opens (Opens)
拍手喝采が起こる
A round of applause erupts
快感です
It feels good
(い！) ロウソクを持って
(1!) Hold the candles
(に！) ドレス纏って！
(2!) Put on your dress!
女王の私のお出ましです！
I, the Queen, have made my appearance!
(よん！) 手を取り合って
(4!) Hand in hand
(ご！) 今は無礼講で
(5!) Let's cast aside formalities for now
私に見せられちゃったら最後です
Once you've shown it to me, it's the end
鮮やかなステップ くるり舞ってワルツ
Vivid steps, twirling and dancing a waltz
惹き込むこのリズムに揺られて
Swaying to this captivating rhythm
この楽しさ癖になるわ
This fun will become a habit
時間切れとか…
Time's up...
やだ！全然足りないってば！
No! It's not nearly enough!
Let's 冥界Halloween Night!
Let's Meikai Halloween Night!
Dancing! Dancing! 一夜の奇妙なメモリー
Dancing! Dancing! A strange memory of one night
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ 冥界Halloween Night!
Rat-ta-ta, Rat-ta-ta, Meikai Halloween Night!
Sweety! Sweety! おもむろに頬張るキャンディー
Sweety! Sweety! Suddenly stuffing candies in my mouth
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ 甘美のショータイム
Rat-ta-ta, Rat-ta-ta, A sweet showtime
うたかたの夢 淡い霧の中溶けて
Transitory dreams melting into the faint mist
青白い頬を涙が伝った
Tears ran down the pale cheeks
この歌は誰のため？自問自答の末
Who is this song for? After soul-searching
禁断の箱を開けたら
If you open the forbidden box
魔法を使っちゃおうかな
Maybe I'll use some magic
Dancing! Dancing! 陽気にハッピーなメロディー
Dancing! Dancing! A cheerful and happy melody
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ 冥界Halloween Night!
Rat-ta-ta, Rat-ta-ta, Meikai Halloween Night!
Swinging! Swinging! ゾッとして愉快なアイロニー
Swinging! Swinging! A spine-chilling and pleasant irony
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ 狂騒のショータイム
Rat-ta-ta, Rat-ta-ta, A rowdy showtime
(Pa Pa Pa) 恐ろしいな
(Pa Pa Pa) How scary
(Pu Pu Pu) 恨めしいな
(Pu Pu Pu) How resentful
夢も重さも忘れてる
Forgetting both dreams and weight
おろろ？
Oh?
(Pa Pa Pa) 美味しそうな
(Pa Pa Pa) Looks delicious
(Pu Pu Pu) 魂だわ
(Pu Pu Pu) What a soul
Welcome! さあ、踊ろうよ This is Halloween Night!
Welcome! Come on, let's dance, This is Halloween Night!
ハロウィンパーティー、いかがでしたでしょうか？
How did you enjoy the Halloween party?
ちゃんとこちら側の王国に戻ってこられていますか？
Have you managed to return to the kingdom on this side safely?
冥界の女王様に気に入られてしまうと、魂を奪われてしまって帰ってこられませんからね。
If the Queen of the Underworld takes a liking to you, she'll steal your soul, and you won't be able to come back.
戻ってこられてラッキーでした。…なんて。
You were lucky to be able to return. ...Just kidding.
あ、今日のお話はどうでしたか？
Ah, how did you like today's stories?
楽しかったでしょうか？
I hope they were fun.
私が特にお気に入りは、探偵のお話でして。
My personal favorite was the detective story.
今回お聞かせできてとっても嬉しかったです。
I was very happy to be able to share it with you.
そうだ、いつかあなたのお話も聞かせてくださいね。
That's right, please let me hear your stories someday too.
もしかすると、あの本にあなたのお話も書き記されるかもしれませんよ。
Who knows, your stories might even be recorded in that book one day.
なんといっても、摩訶不思議な本ですから。
After all, it is a very mysterious book.
何が起こるか、司書である私にも分かりません。
Even as the librarian, I don't know what might happen.
さて、そろそろお時間ですね。
Well, it's about time.
またお話が聞きたくなりましたら、
If you ever wish to hear more stories,
いつでもこの王国図書館へお越しください。
please visit this Kingdom Library at any time.
それでは。さようなら。
Until then. Farewell.
ハジマリはきっと ひとつの願い
It surely begins with a single wish
Shirakami Fubuki 1st Solo Live FBKINGDOM ANTHEM
LIVE Blu-ray 発売決定！
LIVE Blu-ray release confirmed!
すこん部の皆さん！準備はできてますか？
Everyone in Sukonbu! Are you ready?
『Say!ファンファーレ!』、いきますよ！
'Say! Fanfare!', here we go!
せーの！ ほら どっか 行こう 顔上げて
One, two! Look, let's go somewhere, lift your head
みんなで手を取れば ハイ！
If we all take hands, hey!
まだまだ道半ば 世界を超えよう
We're still only halfway there, let's go beyond the world
ハイ！ ほら 推し推し様 止まらない
Hey! Look, my dear oshi, won't stop
全力ですから！
Because I'm giving it my all!
夢を書き換えたら
If we rewrite our dreams,
追いかけ続けよう 共に繋ぐファンファーレ
let's keep chasing them, the fanfare that connects us
宝物に気づか 自分自身の輝きを見失った時には
Notice the treasure, when you've lost sight of your own sparkle
思い出してね 僕らの星座は 君がいるから輝く
Please remember, our constellation shines because you are here
Oh Yeah! 無数の星の中
Oh Yeah! Amidst countless stars
Oh Yeah! 光を君がくれた
Oh Yeah! You gave me light
Oh Yeah Yeah Yeah...
もっと超えていけるさ
We can go even further
Oh Yeah! 超新星 起こせ今
Oh Yeah! Cause a supernova right now
Oh Yeah! 何度だって跳べる
Oh Yeah! I can jump as many times as it takes
Oh Yeah Yeah Yeah...
これは紛れもなく僕らの奇跡
This is undeniably our miracle
Hi Friends!
Blu-ray 発売決定!! 詳細は後日！お楽しみに!!
Blu-ray release confirmed!! Details coming soon! Look forward to it!!
ベストウィッシュ！すこん部ー！
Best wishes! Sukonbu!